enscape3d.com 2019-07-15

# Privacy - Enscape™

**Data protection**

We appreciate your visit to our website and your interest in our company and our products. In doing so, we respect your privacy and ensure the protection of your personal information by processing your personal information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and the applicable privacy laws.

You can visit our websites without telling us who you are. In order to display our web pages, you are only obliged to provide the data transmitted to our server (see “Logfiles”) by your browser. Other personal information about you will only be stored if you voluntarily enter it on the website, or use the appropriate features, e.g. for entries via our contact or application forms.  
  
---  
 **Contact and other online forms**

You may enter your personal information on our website to contact us or to order a trial version of our software. Only data, indicated with an asterisk, is data that is considered to be obligatory and that you are required to provide. Any additional data submitted may be helpful in processing your request, but it is not mandatory (optional). With your consent, these data will only be used and stored for the purpose of processing your message (Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. a DSGVO) or for carrying out your order/request (Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. b DSGVO).

When ordering a trial version, we also process personal data for marketing purposes within the framework of Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DSGVO. You may object to advertising use at any time with future effect.  
  
 **Orders, customer account**

To place an order, you must register as a customer. For registration, the data provided with an asterisk must be entered as mandatory information. We process this data for the purpose of carrying out your order and for the necessary communication with you, as well as to guarantee support (Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. b DSGVO). The specification of further data may be helpful for the processing of your order, but it is not compulsory (voluntary information, Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. a DSGVO). You can have your user account deleted by sending an e-mail to us under the contact details listed under “Responsible”. We carry out the deletion after termination of any existing contractual relationship, taking into account any existing statutory retention requirements. We also process your personal data for marketing purposes within the framework of Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DSGVO. You may object to advertising use at any time with future effect.  
  
 **Webinars**

You have the opportunity to participate in webinars or to book a webinar via our platform. For this, registration is required and the mandatory information, indicated with an asterisk, that is provided and is for the purpose of carrying out the event, is collected and processed; any further data provided outside the mandatory information required will be considered advantageous, but not mandatory (voluntary information). The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. b und a DSGVO. The event will be carried out via a technical platform of a technical service provider, which processes the personal data on our behalf. We use this data solely for the purpose of conducting the webinar (and any related billing purposes).  
  
 **Forum**

Our forum can be read without requiring registration. If you would like to actively participate in the forum, you must register yourself by entering your e-mail address, a password of your own choice, and your own username. There is no constraint placed in choosing a username, and the use of a pseudonymous is possible. You can complete your profile by volunteering further information or by providing a photo of yourself. These data (except for the e-mail address) will, with your consent, be publicly displayed in the forum for all other visitors (Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. a DSGVO).  
When you sign up for a forum account, we’ll store all the information associated with your account, such as your public posts, likes, private messages, etc. that are required to run the forum, up until the time your account is deleted. The legal basis is Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DSGVO.  
If you delete your account, your account will no longer be available and no profile will be visible to other users, but your public statements, in particular, contributions to the forum, will continue to be visible to all readers, but will be marked in the forum with ??? instead. All other data will be deleted.  
  
 **Online application**

By using the online application service you are leaving the Enscape website. Data processing, under the data protection law, is then no longer under the responsibility of Enscape GmbH, but under the responsibility of Personio GmbH. We can therefore not influence the type and scope of the data processing undertaken. You can apply to us in writing, as well as directly through our website. It is compulsory to provide information for data fields that are marked with an asterisk. The provision of further personal data may be helpful in processing your application, but is not mandatory (voluntary information). The legal basis for data processing is Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. b DSGVO (Initiation of Employment). You have the option of sending us your application document, such as a CV, certificates of qualifications, etc. confidentially by post. Alternatively, you can also send these documents directly over the Internet via the website’s online application, submitting the files in question which will be encrypted (TLS). Your information provided during the application process is processed by Personio on behalf of Enscape. Personio GmbH stores data exclusively on ISO-certified servers in Germany. Further measures to ensure compliance with data protection law are regulated under a contract for processing orders (Art. 28 GDPR). Any use for other purposes, or the passing on to any third parties (except the obligated after the DSGVO Dienstleister) does not take place, unless expressly agreed to by you (consent). Application documents are stored for the duration of employment with due observance of legal retention periods. In the event of cancellation, we will delete application documents no later than six months after the cancellation, or we will send the non-electronic documents back to you.  
  
 **Cookies**

Cookies are very small text files used by internet sites, which your browser stores on your computer and allows certain information to flow through the site that sets the cookie (here, through us). Cookies can not run programs or transmit viruses to your computer.  
Transient cookies are automatically deleted when you close the browser. These include in particular the session cookies. These store a so-called session ID, with which various requests from your browser can be assigned to the common session. This will allow your computer to be recognized when you return to our website. The session cookies are deleted when you log out or close the browser.  
Persistent cookies are automatically deleted after a specified period, which may differ depending on the cookie. You can delete the cookies in the security settings of your browser at any time.  
This information is used to optimize our offerings and to offer you more comfort while browsing our pages. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DSGVO.  
You can set your internet browser to notify you as soon as a web server wants to send a cookie to you. You can then agree to the acceptance of the cookie, or reject it. You can configure your browser settings according to your wishes. For example, you can choose to decline the acceptance of third-party cookies, or all cookies. Please be aware that you may not be able to use all the features of this site if cookies are disabled. You can find out more about this in the help system of your Internet browser.  
  
 **Links on social media platforms**

Our website refers to our other pages on various social media platforms. We point out that, by clicking on these links, you leave our website and, at the same time, the scope of this privacy policy. Only the respective privacy statements and terms of use of the operator of the social media platform apply on the social media platforms.  
  
 **Social Media Plugins**

We use the following social media plugins: LinkedIn, Facebook, Google+, Twitter, Reddit, Pinterest  
Only by clicking on the button will the content of the plugin be transmitted to the respective operator of the social media platform. We have no control over the collected data and data processing operations of the respective operator of the social media platform, nor are we aware of the full scope of data collection, purposes, and retention periods of the respective operator of the social media platform. The transmitted data is (as far as we know) the URL of the page visited and the IP address and/or another platform-dependent identifier you have used. At Xing, no personal data is transmitted, not even IP addresses (statement from Xing). If you are also logged in on the respective social media platform, the respective operator can assign the visit to your user account on the accounts associated website.  
The plug-ins allow us to interact with social networks and other users so that we can improve our offerings whilst also making it more interest for you as a user. The legal basis for the use of the plug-ins is Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DSGVO.  
The purpose and scope of the data collection by the respective operator of the social media platform and the further processing and use of the data by the operator, as well as your related rights and setting options to protect your privacy, should be referred to via the  privacy policy of the respective operator of the social media platform:  
  
  * Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA; http://www.facebook.com/policy.php. Facebook ist nach EU-US-Privacy-Shield zertifiziert
  * Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; https://twitter.com/privacy. Twitter ist nach EU-US-Privacy-Shield zertifiziert.
  * Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountainview, California 94043, USA; https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/?hl=de. Google ist nach EU-US-Privacy-Shield zertifiziert.
  * LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; http://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy. LinkedIn ist nach EU-US-Privacy-Shield zertifiziert.
  * Pinterest Europe Ltd., Palmerston House, 2nd Floor, Fenian Street, Dublin 2, Irland; https://policy.pinterest.com/de/privacy-policy
  * Reddit, Inc., Legal Department, 548 Market Street #16093, San Francisco, California 94104, USA; https://www.redditinc.com/policies/privacy-policy. Reddit ist nach EU-US-Privacy-Shield zertifiziert.

 **Logfiles**

Each time you access our site, we collect the following information about your computer: the IP address of your computer, the request of your browser, and the time of this request. As part of this request, it also records the status and amount of data transferred, along with product and version information about your browser, as well as the operating system of your computer. We keep track of which website referred to our site. The IP address of your computer is stored only for the time you use the website after which, it is immediately deleted or anonymized by shortening. The remaining data is stored for a limited period of time. We use this data for the operation of our website, in particular, to detect and eliminate website errors, to determine the utilization of the website, and to make adjustments or improvements to it (legal basis: Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DSGVO). **Google Analytics**  
This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, text files that are stored on your computer that allow us to analyze the use of our website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually sent to a Google server in the USA, where it can be stored. However, in the event that IP anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address when provided from within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area, will be shortened before being sent to the Google server in the USA. Only in exceptional circumstances will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the US, where it will be shortened.

On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to gather more information about website and  Internet service activity to provide related services for the website operator. The IP address provided by Google Analytics as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. You can prevent the storage of cookies by adjusting the corresponding setting of your browser software; however, please note that, if you do this you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest possible extent. In addition, you may prevent Google the collection of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading the browser plug-in available under the following link [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en] and install or alternatively by clicking on the following link to set a so-called opt-out cookie.  
<a href=”javascript:gaOptout()”> Disable Google Analytics via opt-out cookie </a>  
This website uses Google Analytics with the extension “_anonymizeIp ()”. As a result, IP addresses are shortened in order to exclude a direct personal reference.  
We use Google Analytics to analyze and regularly improve the use of our website. With the statistics, we can improve our offerings whilst also making it more interesting for you as a user. In exceptional cases in which personal data is transferred to the US, Google has submitted to the EU-US Privacy Shield. The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DSGVO.  
For more information about Google’s data processing, please see the Google Privacy Policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en

 **Pardot Marketing Automation**

We use Pardot from Pardot LLC, 950 E. Paces Ferry Rd Suite 3300 Atlanta, GA 30326, USA (“Pardot”). Pardot is a special software for the collection and evaluation of the use of a website by its visitors. Pardot participates in the Safe Harbor program of the US Department of Commerce. For more information about Pardot’s handling of personal data from the European Union, see the Safe Harbor Notice: www.pardot.com/company/legal/safe-harbor-notice. For general information about the Safe Harbor program, visit www.export.gov/safeharbor. There, you can also view Pardot’s current Safe Harbor certification. When visiting our website, Pardot records your click path and creates an individual usage profile using a pseudonym. For this purpose, cookies are used to enable the recognition of your browser. By agreeing to the use of cookies when you first use our website, or by confirming the so-called Cookie Acceptance Banner, or by the continued use of our website, you also agree to the use of cookies by Pardot. You can revoke your consent at any time and with immediate effect. Please contact the above responsible body. In addition, you can deactivate the creation of pseudonymous user profiles at any time by configuring your Internet browser so that cookies of the domain “pardot.com” are not accepted. However, this may result in some limitations in the features and usability of our offerings. **Facebook Custom Audiences**  
Our website uses the Facebook Remarketing feature “Custom Audiences” of Facebook Inc. (“Facebook”). This allows users of the website to be shown interest-based advertisements (“Facebook Ads”) as part of their visit to the social network Facebook, or other websites that also use the process. We are interested in showing you advertisements that are of interest to you in order to make our website more interesting for you.  
Due to the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection to the Facebook server. We have no control over the extent and the further use of the data resulting from  the use of this tool by Facebook, and we, therefore, inform you  according to our understanding: through the integration of Facebook Custom Audiences, Facebook receives the information that you have accessed the corresponding pages of our website, or have clicked on an ad from us. If you are registered with a service of Facebook, Facebook can assign the visit to your associated account. Even if you are not registered with Facebook or have not logged in, there is a chance that the provider will find out and store your IP address as well as other identifying features.  
Disabling the “Facebook Custom Audiences” feature is available (here and) to logged-in users at https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_.  
The legal basis for the processing of your data is Art. 6 Abs. 1 S. 1 lit. f DS-GVOO. For more information about data processing through Facebook, please visit https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy.

Olark

We use a live chat tool from Olark by Habla, Inc. 245 Ramona St. Palo Alto, CA 94301. This tool allows our site visitors to chat directly with enscape3d.com employees so that they can aquire answers to questions they may have. For details on the handling of your personal data by Olark, as well as your rights in this regard, please refer to the privacy policy of Olark (https://www.olark.com/tos).

 **Embedded content from third parties (YouTube, etc.)**

If third-party content, such as YouTube, is displayed on our websites, the provision of your IP address and the contents displayed under “Logfiles” to the third-party provider are required for the provision of this content and to display it in your browser. We have no influence on data processing of the third party. If you are logged in to the third party with an associated user account, the third party may assign your user behavior to that associated user account. If necessary, the third party stores your data as usage profiles and uses them for the purpose of advertising, market research, and/or customization of its website. Opposition rights against the formation of these user profiles must be addressed to the third party.  
For more information on the purpose and scope of the third-party data collection and its processing, please refer to its privacy policy. There you will also get further information about your rights and settings for the protection of your privacy:

  * Youtube, LL.C., 901 Cherry Avenue, Second Floor, San Bruno, CA 94066, USA; https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites. YouTube is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield.

 **Revocation of consent and objection to data processing**

If you have given us consent, you can withdraw it at any time with immediate effect.  
Insofar as we base the processing of your personal data on the balance of interests, you may object to the processing. In the event of such a disagreement, we ask you to explain the reasons why we should not process your personal data as we have done. In the case of your justified objection, we will examine the situation and will either discontinue or adapt the data processing, or point out to you our compelling legitimate reasons on which we would continue the processing.  
You may object to the processing of your personal data for advertising and data analysis purposes at any time.  
You can send your cancellation or objection under the contact data under “Responsible Person”.

 **Your Rights**

You have the following rights with respect to the personal data concerning you:

  * Right to information
  * Right to rectification or cancellation
  * Right to a restriction of processing
  * Right to object to the processing
  * Right to data portability.

You also have the right to complain to us about the processing of your personal data via a Data Protection Authority.

 **Scope of this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy informs you about data processing of our website at https://enscape3d.com. Please note that by clicking on links you can leave our website and thus also leave the scope of this privacy policy. On other linked websites, only the respective privacy statements and terms of use of the operator of the linked website will apply.

 **Responsible**

Enscape GmbH, Erbprinzenstr. 27, 76133 Karlsruhe, Phone: +49 721/132 060 – 60, Fax: +49 721/170 293 – 019, Email: info@enscape3d.com

Data protection officer: datenschutzanfragen@xdsb.de, or under our postal address with the addition “The Data Protection Representative”

You wish to Opt out of Tracking?

Google: Disallow Google Analytics to track me
